it started at the same time as at the
началось одновременно как
same time Well, at the same time ours
одновременно Ну вот одновременно наши
entered Slavyansk and at the same time the
зашли в Славянск и одновременно э
Ukrainian dryers began to fly on
украинские сушки начали летать на
wait What kind of yours entered
подождите Какие ваши зашли в
Slavyansk our Russia What were your then
Славянск наши Россия Какие ваши тогда
Russians you were Donetsk
россияне вы были Донецкие
just
просто
hello Hello you have such a
здравствуйте Здравствуйте у вас такой
beautiful flag pogla Here is the first Russian
красивый флаг погла Вот первый русский
Who took it and stroked it  I didn’t just
Кто взял и погладил флаг а не просто его
buy a flag and
так купил и
unroll it. Well, you have nothing either. Or is it
развернул Ну у вас тоже ничего Или это у
your wallpaper, this is the wallpaper, you see them, you touch
вас обои это обои видите они их трогаешь
them. Well, they’re not glued, but they came unglued,
они Ну да не приклеенные да отклеились
the temperature here was jumping. Where did I come
температура тут прыгала Вы
from from Donetsk? And now, where were
откуда я с Донецка понял А сейчас где
you born in Donetsk, I understood?  I’m originally from
ты родился в Донецке понял я родом из
Rostov, but I’ve been living in London for 18 years.
Ростова но уже 18 лет живу в Лондоне
In 2 years, Ukraine will be the twentieth.
через 2 года будет двадцатой
And why? Well, because the
Украину А почему Ну потому что за
truth is that Russia is the aggressor behind Ukraine. I
Украиной правда Россия агрессор напала я
understand that I was born in Russia, yes, but I
понимаю что я родился в России да но я
shouldn’t support this
не должен поддерживать этот
terrorist
террористический
regime. Well, you probably think so then
режим Ну вы так наверно думаете потом
that  you moved because of this, why do
что вы переехали из-за этого ну почему у
I have parents in Rostov and what?
меня родители в Ростове и что
Well, my parents are of the same opinion as you,
Ну родители такого же мнения Как и вы
that my parents are of the same opinion as
что-что родители такого же мнения как и
you, mom is like me and dad is a little bit of a
вы мама как я а папа немножко он
Putinist,
путинист
he’s a little bit not either for or
он нуно немножко не бывает либо за либо
against  Well, he’s so
проти Ну он так
moderate Well, I most likely understood your pa
умеренный Ну я скорее всего за вашего па
But the question is interesting, most likely that’s
понял А вот вопрос интересно скоре всего
the way it is,
так оно есть
yes I’m interested in figuring it out I was
да Вот мне интересно разобраться Я
just talking to the Ukrainians, I installed
просто с украинцами общался я ставил
Ukraine VPN, I installed it and talked with them for 2
Украину VPN ставил и общался с ними 2
hours Yes, they tell me such a thing
часа Да они мне рассказывают такую вещь
that
что
Uh  it wasn’t Ukraine that shelled the Donbass,
Ээ это не Украина обстреливала Донбасс
it was April 12, 1914, it was
это 12 апреля четырнадцатого года э
Russian militants that
стрелков рхи российские боевики
fired at the shooters, it was reported that Russian
обстреливала донес Да не что российские
militants invaded the territory of the Donetsk
боевики вторглись на территорию Донецкой
region, that there were no hostilities before that, I’m
области что до этого никаких боевых
interested, you
действий не было Вот мне интересно Вы
can, I want some arguments for them,
можете Я хочу для них какие-то аргументы
really  until April 12,
ээ реально до 12 апреля четырнадцатого
1914, when the Strelkov Girkin captured
года когда стрелков гиркин захватил
Slavyansk and other cities. Yes, were there
Славянск и другие города Да были ли
any military operations in the Donetsk
какие-то боевые действия в Донецкой
region
области
? Of course not, that is, it turns out that until
м Конечно нет то есть получается пока
the Russians got in there and began to
россияне не залезли туда и не начали
capture the cities, there were no military operations
захватывать города боевых действий не
Yes, no, that’s not the point  Look even before
Да нет не в этом дело Смотрите ещё до
As you say, to Slavyansk to Girkin
Как вы говорите до Славянска до гиркина
to Strelkov Yes,
до Стрелкова Да вот уже на Донецком
Ukrainian dryers were already flying in Donetsk and showing that
сушки летали украинские и показывали что
if you wake up somewhere to the left or right there,
если вы куда-нибудь влево или вправо там
Well, you will be there and they flew
проснетесь Ну там вам будет и они летали
at a distance Well, at an altitude, he
на расстоянии Ну на высоте неправильно
said incorrectly at an altitude of nine  floor again,
сказал на высоте девяти этаже ещё раз я
I heard you correctly, yes, there
правильно я правильно Вас услышал да что
were no military operations there before the invasion of the Strelkovaya Girka company in the Donetsk region,
область там не было
well, why would I lie or invent, the
да ну зачем буду врать или придумывать
Russians just tell me that there weren’t any,
просто россияне мне говорят что нет были
and Strelkov Girkin had already come to help, like
и стрелков гиркин уже пришёл помочь типа
fight No, that’s all  it started after
воевать Нет это всё началось после
the Maidan No, it’s clear, yes But like
Майдана Нет так это понятно да Но типа
some kind of rallies Yes, but the war, the war, the war was
какие-то митинги Да но война войну войну
started by the Russians when they came and began to
начали россияне когда пришли и начали
take over the
захватывать
cities Well, I told you a little wrong,
города Ну это я Вам чуть неправильно
it started at the same time as
сказал это началось одновременно как
at the same time
одновременно
Well, at the same time ours entered
Ну вот одновременно наши зашли в
Slavyansk and
Славянск и
at the same time Ukrainian drying  started to
одновременно украинские сушки начали
fly What kind of yours came into
летать Какие ваши зашли в
Slavyansk ours What were your then
Славянск наши ро Какие ваши тогда
Russians you were Donetsk It’s just that you were Donetsk
россияне вы были Донецкие Просто вы
residents yes yes the Russians came into
дончане были да да россияне зашли в
Slavyansk captured someone else’s
Славянск захватили чужой
city violated international
город нарушили международное
law Yes they invaded someone else’s
законодательство Да вторглись в чужое
state so it turns out
государство так получается
what month are you telling me
это какой месяц вы говорите мне
April April 12,
апрель 12 апреля 2014
2014  Well, then, too, there
года ну и тогда же тоже там боевых
were no hostilities in Slavyansk. Well, there were
действий не было в Славянске Ну как были
some dead, and there were already
и погибшие были да и были были уже
hostilities; it all started. And then they
боевые действия всё началось И тогда ж
gathered that they were happy about the safety of this
собралась это рада безопасности этой
Ukrainian and accepted that the start of an
украинской и приняли что о начале
anti-terrorist operation.
антитеррористической операции
Yes,
Да ну
no, most likely everything at the same time  this
Нет скорее всего одновременно всё это
happened Well, at the same time,
происходило Ну как одновременно ещё раз
look again, here are the Russians Yes, there were shooters until
смотрите вот россияне Да стрелков до
Strelkovaya Gir before the capture of Slavyansk and
Стрелковая Гир до захвата Славянска и
other cities, no military operations
других городов никаких боевых действий
in Donetsk and Lugansk I was in 10 years
на Донецке и Луганске Я за 10 лет я
Why did I start supporting Ukraine Yes, I
Почему начал поддерживать Украину Да я
started to figure it out I was also told that
начал разбираться Мне тоже говорили там
Ukraine was shelling there I was watching while
Украина обстреливала Я смотрел пока
the Russians did not come in and start
россияне не зашли и не начали
capturing the cities, there were no military
захватывать города никаких боевых
actions, of course, when
действий не было Конечно когда уже идут
military operations are already underway, there are already some
боевые действия там уже есть какие-то
arrows. That is, it turns out, look, there
стрел Вот то есть получается смотрите в
were no military
Славянске не было никаких боевых
operations in Slavyansk until Ukraine started
действий пока Украина не начала
provocations in Donetsk, as there were no military
провокации в Донецке как не было боевых
operations  in Slavyansk on April 12 there were already
действий в Славянске 12 апреля уже были
military operations And the seizure of
боевые действия И захват
administrative buildings and shootouts with
административных зданий и перестрелки с
paratroopers like yes Well, they
десантниками типа было да Ну вам же
probably didn’t tell you everything before
наверное не всё рассказывали до того как
Girkin came to Slavyansk,
зашёл гиркин в Славянск приезжали
buses, trains arrived, thank God the guys stopped the trains,
автобусы поезда слава Богу ребята поезда
Western Ukraine came, what trains
приезжали Западной Украины какие поезда
from Western Ukraine to  Slavyansk came
из Западной Украины в Славянск приезжали
Hello to Donetsk Which ones are in Donetsk Show me
Алло в Донецк Какие в Донецк Покажи вот
and show me where to read photos of
да покажи мне где прочитать фото поезда
these trains And so on about this train
вот этих И так дальше про этот поезд
when the train arrived in Donetsk in Western
когда приехал поезд в Донецк в Западной
Ukraine show me the train they weren’t allowed into Donetsk
Украине покажи ну поезд их в Донецк не
on YouTu I don’t know I was reputed look
пустили в YouTu Я не знаю я слыл смотри
Crimeans  They say that trains of Friendship went to Crimea They
крымчане Говорят что в Крым ездили
say Donetsk is a myth,
поезда Дружбы тут говорят Донецк это миф
there is no such thing, there
нету такого никаких поездов не
were no trains Well, a myth, a myth is not a myth, look,
было Ну миф миф не миф смотри забей
please forget it In the tube Right sector, the center of the
пожалуйста В тубе Правый сектор центр
city of Donetsk and buses again, again
города Донецк и автобусы ещё раз ещё раз
Look, you say trains Trains
Смотри ты ты говоришь поезда Поезда -
are fake trains -  this is fake, this is
это фейк поезда - это фейк это
definitely true I have been dealing with these trains for a long time, there
однозначно Я уже давно с этими поездами
were no trains,
разбирался никаких поездов не было да
but now in Ukraine these are all citizens of
Во теперь в Украине это это всё граждане
Ukraine, even if they were Ukrainian citizens. When they
Украины даже если бы граждане Украины
came to other cities, these were all
Приезжали в другие города это всё
citizens of Ukraine. They have the right
граждане Украины Они имеют право
to hold political events.
проводить политические мероприятия Да
Just like the Donetsk people.  they have the type to
так же как наме дончане имеют типа
come to Lugansk and carry out provocations no
приехать в Луганск и проводить прово нет
look provocations are not provocations there
смотри провокации не провокации это уже
are already special bodies that
есть специальные органы которые
are looking into whether there were any provocations
разбираются Было ли какие-то провокации
or not provocations yes well again
или не провокации да нуно ещё раз
no military operations Yes none Yes
никаких боевых действий Да никаких Да
nowhere the army did not kill anyone Yes
нигде ни армии ничего никого не уби Да
the Russians have not yet  started a war in the Donbass
пока русские не начали войну на Донбассе
Well, it turns out well, well, this is where everything was going,
Ну так получается ну к этому всё и шло
look, it wasn’t going well, we can’t
смотрите шло не шло это мы не можем
say whether it was going or not going We see what the
сказать шло оно или не шло Мы видим что
Russians did, we can’t Well, if the
русские сделали не можем Ну если бы
Right Sector had brought a
Правый сектор заехал бы в
political party to Donetsk Well, one
Донецк политическую партию Ну одну
second, well, you
секунду ну вы
gov here in the yub please Well there is no
гово вот в юбе пожалуйста Ну нету там ни
train or Friendship there, no war
поезда ни Дружбы там ни войны хорошо не
was good Well everything was not good forget
было Ну всё хорошо не было забейте в юбе
there is interest in the yube The right sector came to
там интереса Правый сектор приехал в
Donetsk on the road to the very center of
Донецк на са в самый центр площадь
Lenin Square the grooves arrived with the right sector
Ленина пазики приехали с правым сектором
and they decided how to do it  well, well,
и они решили тут как бы ну сделать Ну
in short, shake the city, try to shake the
короче качнуть город попытаться качнуть
city, it didn’t work out for them.
город у них это ничего не получилось
Now again, look at this,
Теперь ещё раз значит смотрите вот это
if yes, this is all speculation,
если бы да это это всё домыслы та если
if Russia had not started the war, then it would all have
бы Россия не начало войну то оно всё бы
been heading towards this; this is all nonsense; this is an
к этому шло это всё брехня это
excuse Yes  we can only
оправдание Да мы можем только фактами
operate with facts, yes, before Russia there was no war,
оперировать да до России никакой войны
no right sector, no one,
не было никакой правый сектор никого не
yes. And when Russia came, yes, we have been at
да А когда Россия пришла да имеем уже
war for about 10 years already, so it
сколько 10 лет войну так
turns out Well, no, it’s like it’s not a
получается Ну нет это как бы не война
war; it’s not a war;
война это никто не обозначал причём как
war erases
не обозначал Ну смотри Это война стирают
cities from the land Yes, shelling is a war of
города с земель Да обстрелы это война
armies when two armies are at war Yes, this is a
армии когда две армии воюют Да это
war So we don’t have two armies in our country
война Так у нас не две армии во
Well, yes, three more North Korean
у на А ну да три ещё северокорейская
North Korean Yes
северокорейская Да у
we have I won’t say to the end
нас Я до конца не буду говорить что
what kind of army we have  The Russian Federation is at war
какая у нас армия есть у нас воюет
and Well, half of the
и Ну пол
European Union, not a single army of the
Евросоюза ни одна ни одна армия
European Union except the Ukrainian one is fighting. And
Евросоюза кроме украинской не воюет А
look, the North Koreans are fighting,
смотрите а Северо Северо корейцы воюют
but that’s not what interests me now. I want to
но меня сейчас не это интересует Я хочу
figure it out. You’re really very good
разобраться Вот вы реально очень хорошо
that you are an adequate person from Donetsk, I
что вы адекватный человек из Донецка я
can for myself as a citizen  Russian
могу для себя как гражданин Российской
Federation to put together the right puzzle, yes, that
Федерации сложить правильный пазл да то
is, as I am now stating my
есть я как я утверждаю сейчас своё
opinion, it
мнение что
turns out that Russia started this war.
получается Россия начала эту войну
Russia came and began to seize
Россия пришла и начала захватывать
buildings, seize, displace uh mayors, and
здания захватывать смещать ээ мэров Да
put some bandits in charge of the
ставить каких-то бандитов управлять
cities. After all, I looked. Yes, for example, not the
городами Ведь я посмотрел Да например не
Donetsk regional council, not the Lugansk  the
Донецкий областной совет не Луганский
regional Council nor the Donetsk City
областной Совет ни Донецкий городской
Council did not accept Lugansk anything
совет не принимал Луганск ничего с
good about Donetsk neither the Donetsk
хорошо про Донецк нени Донецкий
City Council nor the Donetsk Regional
городской совет ни Донецкий областной
Council did not adopt any resolution
совет не принимал Никакое постановление
on the Donetsk People's Republic Yes,
о Донецкой Народной Республике Да пришли
some armed people came from Russia and
какие-то вооружённые люди из России да
said that now this council
сказали что теперь короче этого совета
will not be shorter and this  there were deputies elected by the
не будет а это были депутаты избранные
entire Donetsk region Yes, by all the people of the
всей Донецкой областью Да всеми людьми
Donetsk region they did not support
Донецкой области они не поддержали
any DPR And so then some
никакой ДНР И так дальше пришли какие-то
Russians came, that’s who was the first head of
Русский вот кто был перши первым главой
the DPR
ДНР
I could be wrong Gubarev I forget these
я могу ошибаться Губарев я забываю эти
names was the real head it was
фамилии был настоящим главой это
Zakharchenko before Zakharchenko before Zakharchenko
Захарченко до Захарченко до Захарченко
Zakharchenko was appointed already in the
был не Захарченко поставили уже в
month of August when
августе месяце когда к минским
everything was going towards the Minsk agreements before Zakharchenko was
соглашениям всё шло до Захарченко был
beard beard beard Alexander
бородай бородай бородай Александр
beard Yes, he was sent from Moscow
бородай Да его прислали из Москвы
Moskvich citizen of the Russian Federation
Москвич гражданин Российской Федерации
as the head of the DPR riflemen Moskvich
как главой ДНР стрелков Москвич
citizen of the Russian Federation became
гражданин Российской Федерации стал
Minister of Defense of the
министр обороны
DPR Ministry of Internal Affairs also for a long time no matter for a long time for a
ДНР МВД тоже надолго неважно надолго
short time then they changed there  like so that there
ненадолго потом там поменяли типа чтобы
was at least something local, that is, it
было Хоть что-то из местное да то есть
turns out that the Russians came from
получается да что пришли россияне Из
Moscow and forcibly removed all the
Москвы да силой отстранили всех
deputies elected by all of us in Donetsk,
избранных всеми донча нами депутатов да
and instead of them they began to broadcast on behalf of the
и вместо них начали вещать от имени
Donets people
Донец людей
so a little bit wrong
так немножко не так Ну
Well, you yourself are from Rostov, that’s a little bit  bad
вот вы сами с Ростова вот немножко плохо
history You know, well, Donetsk Lugansk, it’s all
историю Знаете ну Донецк Луганск это всё
figurative, we’ll take it not figuratively And so it
образно мы возьмём не образно А так оно
is Donbass is correct, not not exactly
есть Донбасс правильно не не совсем
Lugansk Lugansk region - this is
Луганска Луганская область - это
the Slobozhanshchina there Yes, there is not the whole
слобожанщина там ещё Да есть и не вся
Donetsk region Donbass Donbass is the
Донецкая область Донбасс Донбасс - это
Donetsk coal basin This is only a
Донецкий угольный бассейн Это только
Geological name
Геологическая такая название
Yes  well, I don’t take it there
Да ну я не беру там
Slavyanogorsk Svyatogorsk it’s all the
Славяногорск Святогорск это всё одно и
same thing no that’s not the
тоже нет не в этом
point all the time
дело всё время
people from birth aspired to
люди с рождения стремились в
Russia they just didn’t give it before Well,
России просто раньше не давали не Ну
look at the question they aspired they didn’t aspire
вопрос смотрите стремились не стремились
Yes for example, I aspired to England I
Да например вот я стремился в англи я
aspired to England I went to  England,
стремился в Англию я поехал в Англию
if a person aspires to Russia, he
если человек стремится в Россию он
leaves for Russia, yes And then the
уезжает в Россию да А тут
Russian army came Yes, they forcibly
что пришла Российская армия Да насильно
overthrew the authorities there, they began to repress
свергла власть там начала репрессировать
people, a bunch of people from Donetsk, I have
людей куча людей из Донецка у меня
friends from Donetsk Yes, some
знакомые есть из Донецка Да одни
moved to Rostov That’s because
переехали в Ростов Вот потому что
relatives here alone left for Kiev
родственники тут одни уехали в Киев
but they left because this
просто по уезжали потому что пришла эта
Russian army came And that’s it And it became impossible to live there
армия Российская И всё И там жить стало
and Why is it impossible Well Why is
невозможно а Почему невозможно Ну Почему
it impossible because the war is already everything and the
невозможно потому что война уже всё да
Russian world came just like in Abkhazia and
русский мир прил также как в Абхазию и
so on, what do you have there now, what’s with the
так дальше что у вас там сейчас что со
Donbass Arena stadium
стадионом донбасс-арена
Well, I  I’m talking to you adequately,
Ну я я же с вами адекватно разговариваю
don’t be rude to me, it’s
вы меня не грубите он не функцие А
not a function. Why doesn’t it function? Yes, we
почему он не функци лиру ет Да у нас
don’t have any matches. Why
матчи никакие не проводят А почему не
don’t they? Well, what kind of matches can there be
проводят Ну какие матчи могут быть во
during hostilities? What kind of matches will
время боевых действий Какие матчи придёт
50,000 people come to the stadium and what-  some
стадион 50.000 человек и туда что-нибудь
skin Pony is good. But for example,
скине Поня хорошо А например
maybe you have some kind of
Может у вас есть какая-то команда
football team there; it’s safer; you’re already
футбольная там же более безопасно уже вы
far away from the front line. Well, how
же далеко Там от линии фронта Ну как
far is it every day that people travel here to
далеко каждый день люди ездят сюда на
work and we go to them in some way to help?
работу и мы к ним ездим кое-как помогаем
Well, I’m talking about mine  I’m saying work Well, well, the
Ну я про свою работу говорю Ну как Ну
same thing in Mariupol There may
тоже самое в мариуполи Там могут быть
also be some kind of provocations Well, look from
тоже какие-то провокации Ну смотрите от
Mariupol next to next across the border Azov
Мариуполя рядом рядом через границу Азов
and Taganrok are generally so close True Well,
и таганрок так вообще близко Правда Ну
how is it there well how much is there
как там ну сколько там
approximately well 40 in short yes very close Yes
примерно ну 40 короче да очень близко Да
why in Azov Taganrog  there are football
почему в Азове Таганроге есть футбольные
teams And in Mariupol
команды А в Мариуполе
No, well, about I don’t know, I’m
Нет ну про Я не знаю я футболом
interested in football, but I’ve never heard about the Taganskaya Team.
увлекаюсь но про таганскую Команду Я
No, that is, everything is
никогда не слышал Не ну то есть там всё
fine there. But where the Russian
нормально А вот там где пришёл русский
world came. Yes, there, somehow, everything is very cha. Well,
мир Да там как-то типа всё очень ча Ну
okay, but in  Tang of the non-Russian world is
хорошо а в Танг не русского мира
still like 90 km there you Well, like
ещё такое себе 90 км там ти Ну как типа
he’s been there for a long time Yes he’s been there for a
он там давно Да он там
long time he’s been there and will be in Taganrog
давно он там был и будет в Таганроге
temporarily yes The question is look like
временно будет да Вопрос такой смотрите
one second I’ll interrupt and then I Well and
одну секунду я я перебью а потом я Ну а
then you’ll say Why was he  what
потом вы скажете А почему был что
was you
был Вы
saying, well, where are you,
говорите ну куда ты
interesting dude, and that’s how all
а интересный чувак да вот вот так всех
these Donetsk people are when you start
этих донецких когда начинаешь
unpacking Yes, none Well, all the
распаковывать Да никакие Вот вам все
Russians are telling us, Yes, this is Ukraine
русские нам рассказывают Да это Украина
Bombed, here are the people from Donetsk,
Бомбила вот человеки из Донецка гово
no Ukrainian troops have bombed,
никакие украинские войска не бомбили
no Donetsk has not attacked yet Yes, so far
никакой Донецк не нападали ещё Да пока
the Russians  They didn’t come, they didn’t start to capture the
россияне не пришли не начали захватывать
cities, of course, then the
города конечно тогда началась
anti-terrorist operation began because
антитеррористическая операция потому что
[ __ ] off the invasion, it was in Crimea and
да пошло вторжение оно в Крыму было а
now it’s gone to the Donetsk Luhansk region, that’s
теперь пошло и в донецку луганскую обла
all.
вот и всё Вот и вся правда
on th instag I don’t know why
ко пись на й instag Я не знаю для чого
this is why you are there to marvel at oce
це то для чого тоб там дивитись на оце
Fes Ale for you one or two or three clicks
Фес Але для тебе оди два або три клика
Ale you trimae me and I will be kaza in me
Але ты тримае мене и я буду каза в мене
there A bunch of fouls and in me there will be a cool
там Купа фолов и в мене буде класный
mood for robiti but cool video  write to th
настр щоб робити но крут вдео пись на й
Instagram popk Andriy like
Instagram попк Андрий вот
this, let me check for you
так давай я тебя чекаю